Guide to the Cornell University miscellaneous pamphlet report and publication collection, 1886-
Cornell University miscellaneous pamphlet report and publication collection
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Cornell University miscellaneous pamphlet report and publication collection, 1886-
ARP 1598
Cornell University
12
Printed Materials, Publications
Division of Rare and Manuscript Collections, Cornell University Library
Catch all collection of various booklets, brochures, and other publications produced by Cornell University. Includes items from different colleges, departments and organizations from across the University.
COLLECTION DESCRIPTION
Catch all collection of various booklets, brochures, and other publications produced by Cornell University. Includes items from different colleges, departments and organizations from across the University.
SUBJECTS
Names:
Cornell Law School; Cornell University; Cornell Cooperative Extension.; Cornell University--Alumni.; Cornell University--Athletics.; Cornell University--Research.; Cornell University--Residential halls.; Cornell University--Students.; Cornell University.Africana Studies and Research Center.; Cornell University.College of Agriculture.; Cornell University.College of Architecture.; Cornell University.College of Arts and Sciences.; Cornell University.College of Engineering.; Cornell University.College of Forestry.; Cornell University.College of Veterinary Medicine.; Cornell University.Libraries.; Cornell University.Medical College.; Cornell University.Reserve Officers' Training Corps.; Cornell University.School of Hotel Administration.; Cornell University.Summer School.; Cornell University.Theatre.; Herbert F. Johnson Museum of Art.; New York State College of Agriculture.; New York State School of Industrial and Labor Relations.; United States.Army.Reserve Officers' Training Corps.
INFORMATION FOR USERS
The majority of the publications are not described at the item level, only a few representative items have been included in the description below the subject categories.
CONTAINER LIST
- Agriculture, 1919-1994 (Box 1)
  Papers about the College of Agriculture and Life Sciences, including brochures, pamphlets, and catalogues
  - List of publications produced by the College, 1919
  - "Program of the Fourth International Congress of Entomology", August 12-18, 1928
  - "Frontiers in Food Research Symposium Proceedings", April 12-13, 1966
  - "A New Name - The New York State College of Agriculture and Life Sciences", 1970
- Architecture, 1915-1943 (Box 2)
  Contains informative booklets about the College of Architecture
  - The Cornell Architect, 1915-1919
- Architecture, 1987-1996 (Box 3)
  Contains informative booklets and brochures about the College of Architecture
  - "The College of Architecture - Annual" Booklet, 1897-1898
  - "Information for Students in the College of Architecture at Cornell University" Booklets, x3, 1913-1916
- Arts and Science, 1906-1993 (Box 4)
  Contains various historic papers including historical booklets, courses of studies, and faculty listings.
  - "The College of Arts and Sciences" Booklet, 1907
  - "The College of Arts and Sciences" Booklet, 1936
  - "Latin American Studies Program" Booklet, 1973
- Athletics, 1897-1979 (Box 5)
  Contains programs, brochures, newspaper clippings, and catalogues for athletic programs and specific games
  - "Department of Physical Training" Booklet, 1908
  - "How Cornell Does It" Booklet, 1911
  - "Dance Festival" Program, 1927
  - The Women's Athletic Association Brochure, 1940
  - "Penn.-Cornell Dual Meet" - The Official Programs, Saturday May 13, 1922
  - "Cornell Athletic Book", 1897
  - "Pennsylvania vs. Cornell - Junior Week" - the Official Programs, 1924
- Business Management, Laboratories, Law, 1886-1986 (Box 6)
  Contains newsletters from SHOALS and the Lab of Ornithology, papers from the Graduate School of Management. Also houses historical papers from beginning of law school.
  - "Report of a Special Committee on the Establishment of a Department of Law", June 1886
  - "The Dedication of Boardman Hall and the Presentation of the Moak Law Library - Proceedings and Addresses", February 1893
- Conservation, Chemistry, 1909-1989 (Box 7)
  Contains catalogues for chemistry, reports, and brochures
  - "The Cornell Corn Congress - Farmers' Week" Brochure, February 22-27, 1909
- Cooperative Extension, 1990s (Box 8)
  Cornell Cooperative pamphlets and catalogues
- Cornell Centennial Theater, 1893-2004 (Box 9)
  Pamphlets and programs for the Cornell Centennial Theater
  - "Programme of the Quarter-Centennial Celebration", October 6-8, 1893
  - "Will Your Name Appear?" Contributors Booklet, 1920
- Engineering, 1961-1985 (Box 10)
  Contains pamphlets and catalogues for the College of Engineering
- Engineering, 1916-2003 (Box 11)
  - Book of Rules of the College of Engineering, 1929-1930
  - The Sibley Journal of Engineering, 1916
- Extramural, Hotel Administration, ROTC, 1892-1981 (Box 12)
  Contains various historical papers from the Hotel School, Extramural Study, and ROTC
  - A Reprint From The Hotel Monthly - "The Story of Statler Hall, $2,550,000 Hotel Education Unit", August 1950
  - Roster of the Cornell University Corps of Cadets, November 1892
- Forestry, 1902-1948 (Box 13)
  Contains historical College of Forestry booklets
  - "Forestry Quarterly," Volume 1, No. 1, 1902
  - "Cornell Forester" Booklets, x5, 1920-1926
  - Newsletters to Cornell Foresters, 1923-1925
- Graduate School, 1953-1997 (Box 14)
  Contains Graduate School handbooks, catalogs, and papers.
- Industrial and Labor Relations, 1947-1997 (Box 15)
  Contains budgets, newsletters, and catalogues regarding the ILR school
- Johnson Museum, 54-72 (Box 16)
  Show catalogues. Kenneth Evett, Arthur Dove, Whistler, Canaletto, William Blake, Jason Seley, Colin Greenly, Insley, Mitchell, Poleskie, David Ruether, The Civilization of Llhuros, The Dr. and Mrs. Milton Lurie Kramer, Piranesi, Goya, John Hortell, George Kolbe.
- Johnson Museum, 1974-1978 (Box 17)
  Newsletters, press releases, and show catalogues. Gary Wojcik, Jack Chen, Directions in Afro-American Art, Cayuga Exotica, Seymour Lipton, Robert S. Sloan, Fifteenth and Sixteenth-Century Prints of Northern Europe, Edwin Dickinson, Arnold Singer, German Renaissance Prints, Far Eastern Art in Upstate New York,
- Johnson Museum, 1970's and 1980's (Box 18)
  Newsletters and show catalogues. Cornell Then, Sculpture Now; Faculty Exhibition; J.M. Hanson; '63 Creates: Interior Visions; Robert Smithson; Dutch Drawings of the Seventeeth Century from a Collection; Wayang Kulit; Don LaViere Turner; Jon Haggins; Golden Day, Silver Night; Carved Images - Art from Africa; Victor Colby; Barrett Gallagher; The Dr. and Mrs. Milton Lurie Kramer Collection; Olaf M. Brauner; Bryan Hunt; Architecture and Media; Abstract Expressionism - The Formative Years; Landscape: New Views.
- Johnson Museum, 1970's and 1980's. (Box 19)
  Show catalogues. Robert P. Coggins, Richards Ruben, New York State Artists Series, Benjamin Hertzberg, Kay Sage, Phil Niblock.
- Johnson Museum, 1978-2002 (Box 20)
  Show catalogues. Gravely Gorgeous: Gargoyles, Grotesques, and the 19th-Century Imagination, Uncommon Threads - Contemporary Artists and Clothing, Common Threads - Art, Identity and Fashion in the 20th Century, Dutch Drawings of the 17th Century, New York State Artists Series, Cornell Then - Sculpture Now, The Handwrought Object, Translations - Photographic Images with New Forms, Louis M. Eilshewmius, Gaston Lachaise, Jason Seley.
- Johnson Museum, 1982-2001 (Box 21)
  Newsletters, annual reports, and show catalogues. Virtue, Vice, and Vanitas; Portraiture in 16th Century Europe; '63 Creates: Interior Visions; Beth B.; Water, Water, Everywhere; Frank Lloyd Wright and the Johnson Wax Buildings; William Blake; Message to the Future; Creative Impulses/Modern Expressions; Johan van der Keuken; J.O. Mahoney; Arthur Wesley Dow; David Johnson; Joel Perlman; Phyllis Cohen; Knots and Nets; Elsie Dinsmore Popkin; Contemporary Art in Czechoslovakia; Cornell Collects; The Origins of French Printmaking; Evelyn Metzger's Yemen; John Hartell; Reflections to Astound - 17th-Century Duth Prints; Animal Imagery in Old Master Prints and Books; Department of Art Faculty Exhibition; Joan Mitchell; American Commemorative Quilts.
- Johnson Museum, 1998-2008 (Box 22)
  Newsletters, annual reports, and show catalogues. Beads and Baubles, A Bountiful Harvest - Agriculture in Prints, Private - Exploring Personal Space, Tiffany, Art from the Islamic World, Constance Kheel, Roy Lichtenstein, By the Light of Butterlamps, Time and a Chair, Pierre-Joseph Redoute, When Reason Sleeps - Goya, The David M. Solinger Collection, Reality Reimagined - Photography Since 1950, Christian Midjo, The Tale of Genji, Frank Barry, The Steven Barbash Collection, Martie Young, Workers' Art Between the Wars.
- Library, 1898-1990 (Box 23)
  Library guides and handbooks.
  - Cornell University Library - General Rules, 1898
- Library, 1957-1996 (Box 24)
  Brochures, handouts, and library information.
- Library, 1953-1976 (Box 25)
  Memos, correspondences, reports.
- Library, 1906-1987 (Box 26)
  Bylaws, memos, reports.
  - Suggestions for using the General Library, Circa 1906
- Library, 1969-1990 (Box 27)
  Brochures, reports, memos, correspondences.
- Library, 1993-1999 (Box 28)
  Library acquisition lists
- Medical College, 1909-1997 (Box 29)
  Contains "premedical guides," CU Medical College Alumni Magazines, and Department of Physiology and Biochemistry Reprints from 1909 to 1914
- Personnel, 1953-1986 (Box 30)
  Contains various documents relating to employment for students, faculty, and staff
- President, V.P., Secretary, Trustees, 1906-1974, 2001-2006 (Box 31)
  Contains various historical correspondences and press releases from people of power in the University, as well as a couple more recent Board of Trustees and Advisory Council pamphlets. Additionally, there is a pamphlet from 1906 and "Biographical Sketches" from 1923 and 1924.
  - Cornell- A Preliminary Program of Proposed Growth, no date
- Public Relations and Information, 1949-2001 (Box 32)
  Contains a variety of press releases, memos, and correspondences
- Research at Cornell, 1941-2009 (Box 33)
  Annual reports, "Cornell's Research Serves the Region and Beyond"
  - The Research Club of Cornell University - Constitution, Membership Lists, Papers, 1941
  - Research at Cornell - Annual Report of the Coordinator of Research, 1961-1962
- Safety, White Museum, Alumni, International Studies, Africana Studies, 1953-1987 (Box 34)
  Miscellaneous papers sorted by folder for these categories
- Spring Day Scoop, Religious Activities, 1935-1981 (Box 35)
  Spring Day Scoop programs and religious pamphlets
  - Spring Day Scoop Programs, 1935-1939
- Student Registration, 1957-1997, 2007 (Box 36)
  Contains brochures, catalogs, orientation booklets, club lists, and various registration-related memos
- Summer Session, 1938-2000 (Box 37)
  Summer session brochures and catalogues
  - Summer Session Booklet, 1938
- Summer Session, 1991-2009 (Box 38)
  Summer session catalogues
- Treasurer, 1955-1980 (Box 39)
  Contains miscellaneous papers, publications, and correspondences from the office of the treasurer
- Uncle Ezra, Senate, Residential Halls, Ombudsman, Calendar, 1929-1988 (Box 40)
  Contains a folder for each category, with miscellaneous documents in each
  - Cornell University Weekly Calendar, x2, October 26, November 2, 1929
  - The Proposed Residential Halls: Cornell University, no date
- University Faculty, 1917-1969 (Box 41)
  Contains various reports, minutes, memos, and correspondences.
  - "Report of the University Faculty to the Board of Trustees in Regard to the Office of Adviser of Women", 1917
  - "Report of Faculty Conference Committee on Military Training", 1933
- University Faculty, 1970-1974 (Box 42)
  Minutes, reports, memos, and correspondences.
- University Faculty, 1965-1976 (Box 43)
- University Faculty, 1976-1977 (Box 44)
- University Faculty, 1965-1984 (Box 45)
- University Faculty, 1983-1989 (Box 46)
  Minutes, reports, memos, correspondences, and various "Academic Integrity" handbooks
- University Faculty, 1985-1992 (Box 47)
- University Faculty, 1965-2002 (Box 48)
  Faculty Handbooks
- University Faculty, 1992-1996 (Box 49)
- Veterinary Medicine, 1919-2002 (Box 50)
  Contains budgets, reports, catalogues, and various brochures from the Veterinary College
  - "The Report of the Conference at the New York State Veterinary College During the Semi-Centennial Celebration of Cornell University", June, 1919
  - "New York State Veterinary College" Budgets, 1947-1952